A Guide to the Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Laboratory Notes, 1935-1974
  - Laboratory notebooks
    - untitled, 1 bound notebook (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Carlsberg Laboratory, Copenhagen Nikrotechnik, 1939 May 15-July 15; 1 bound notebook (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Microfilm of Kern's Ph.D. thesis (in a 5 x 7 permalife envelope), 1958 October (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Phosphatase: Literature search on phosphatase, 1913-1941 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Phosphatase, 1940-1942 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Lymph #1, 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Lymph #2, 1943-1944 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Experiments with fibrinogen, normal human sera, plasma, hemolyzed sera, hemoglobin, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Effect of human plasma, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Preliminary experiments with artificial protein mixtures, 1944-1945 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Bovine serum albumin - lactoglobulin, egg albumin #1, and other experiments, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Egg albumin, ovalbumin experiments, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Egg, human serum, bovine serum albumin and others; NaCl, KCl; amino acids; peptides; urea; hydrozine sulfate; dispersion measurements; density measurements, 1946-1947 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Denaturation experiments Ea-Pa, 1947 1949 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Electrophoresis plakalbumin, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Modified ovalbumin
    - Modified ovalbumin I, 1947-1948 1949 1950 1951 1953 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      Includes MacPherson, Moore, Longsworth reprints; copies of Perlmann, Longsworth correspondence. with Linderstrøm-Lang. Linderstrøm-Lang and Otteson ms.
    - Modified ovalbumin II, 1948-1949 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Collaborative experiments
    Includes patient record; some correspondence indicates electrophoretic work for hospital patient and others; possible collaboration with Dr. Van Dyke, Dr. Dubos, Dr. Tamm, Dr. Trager, Dr. Kunkel.
    - 1948-1950, I (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 1948, II (Box 35, Folder 4)
      BSA-JO4
    - 1950-1951, III (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Copenhagen, 1950 Summer (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Includes 2 bound notebooks; graphs; Korsgaard-Christensen published paper.
  - Immunology ovalbum, 1948-1949 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    Includes typescript draft of Kaminski and Grabar abstract; Walker and Benditt reprint.
  - Dephosphorylation of ovalbumin
    - Dephosphorylation of ovalbumin I, 1950-1951, 1952; I (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Includes MacPherson, Moore, Longsworth reprint.
    - Dephosphorylation of ovalbumin II, 1950, 1951, 1952; II (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Dephosphorylation of ovalbumin III, 1951; III (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Dephosphorylation of ovalbumin IV, 1953; IV (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Phosphatase I, 1951 1952 1954 1955 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Stability of phosphoproteins, 1951 1953 1954 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Casein
    - Casein I, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Includes reprints by others.
    - Casein II, 1953, 1954, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Dephosphorylation of pepsin
    - Dephosphorylation of pepsin I, 1952-1954 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Includes Tiselius, Henschen & Svenson reprint.
    - Dephosphorylation of pepsin II, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Autodigestion of pepsin I, 1952-1953 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Includes Orringer, Lauser and Hollander reprint.
  - Pepsin miscellaneous, 1953-1955 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Urea-Pepsin
    - Urea-pepsin I, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Urea-pepsin II, 1956, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Urea-pepsin III, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Urea-pepsin IV, 1957-1958 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      Includes in Russian: Harrington and Rivers reprint.
  - Amino acid composition
    - Amino acid composition I, 1957-1958 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Amino acid composition II, 1958-1959 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Pepsin Rotation experiments, 1958-1959 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Pepsin miscellaneous experiments, 1958-1959 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Poly-l-methionine experiments 1 bound notebook, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      [1960 notes on Poly-l-methionine while visiting Professor at Weizmann Institute, Israel]
    - Poly-l-methionine experiments, 1960-1961 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Includes 1 item 1961 correspondence (photocopy) Carroll/Perlmann on measurements.
    - Poly-l-methionine, 1960 April-August
      Primarily calculations of ultracentrifugation and diffusion experiments.
      - pp. 1-126 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - pp. 127-219 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - GCl [guanidine hydrochloride] - pepsin (J. Léonis), 1959 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      [name on original outer notebook cover]
    - P-free pepsin, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Pepsin O.B.-S-S-[S-succinylcys], 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      Includes photocopied typescript draft pp. 9-16, 22-37, 44, 54-56 of Kern thesis; some R. Diringer experimental work; typescript draft "Methods" on pepsin treatment in various ways.
  - Pepsinogen preliminary data
    - Pepsinogen I., 1960 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Includes typescript draft of procedure of "Regeneration of DEAE (N-N-diethylamino ethyl cellulose column). Van Vunakis and Herriott published paper on "Structural changes associated with the conversion of pepsinogen to pepsin. ".
    - Pepsinogen II. Nutritional protein preparations. Preparations of pepsinogen on DEAE columns (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Pepsinogen general, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Includes preparations; comparison of: preparations and amino acid residues.
    - Pepsinogen general, 1964 1965-1968 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Miscellaneous experiments including various experiments on pepsinogen activity; typescript draft of Bresler, Glickina, Frankel ms. on "The enzymatic activity of low molecular weight fragments of proteins and the problems of reactive centers of enzymes".
  - Amino acids analyses
    - 1961-1962 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - 1962 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - 1963 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Urea-pepsinogen experiments, 1962-1963 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      Includes Young and Potts published paper.
  - Pepsinogen Optical Rotation
    - Pepsinogen-optical rotation I, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Pepsinogen-optical rotation II, 1961-1962 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Pepsinogen-optical rotation III, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Pepsinogen-optical rotation IV, 1964-1965 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Includes photocopied typescript draft 1963-1964 Research Report by Edward J. Pollack on "Studies of the pepsinogen-pepsin conversion".
  - Pepsinogen Data
    Primarily chromatograms.
    - 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 1969 1971 1973 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - UV [Ultraviolet] - spectra pepsinogen
    - 1961 1963 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      Includes assorted published papers by others.
    - 1963-1964 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Acetylation of Pepsin-Pg [Pepsinogen]
    - Acetylation of pepsin and Pg, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Acetylation of pepsin-pg (Summaries), 1965 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Succinylation of pepsinogen (Summaries), 1965 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Pepsinogen Titration experiments
    - Pepsinogen Titration experiments, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Pepsinogen titrations I Temperature, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Pepsinogen titrations II Summaries, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Pepsinogen reverse titration, 1964-1966 1968 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Back titration summaries, 1965-1966 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Pepsinogen discontinuous titrations, 1965-1967 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Titration calculations, 1965-1967 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      Includes literature search (published papers by others); partial typescript draft with corrections of Perlmann, Oplatka and Katchalsky ms.
  - IMET experiments, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 1, Folder 2)
  - Pepsin-ZPDM
    - Pepsin ZPDM. Procedure etc., 1966-1967 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Pepsin ZPDM. Results etc., 1966-1967 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Includes photocopied typescript draft on Micro-Kjeldahl Nitrogen Analysis procedure.
    - ORD [Optical Rotatory Dispersion] Pepsin; ZPDM-Pepsin, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Pepsin, CN-Pepsin
    - Pepsin, CN-Pepsin I., 1966-1967 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Includes table of contents to hand numbered pages.
    - Pepsin CN-Pepsin II, 1967-1968 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Pg[pepsinogen], CNpg (Box 45)
    - pg, CNpg I, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - pg, CNpg II, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Includes table of contents to hand numbered pages in each folder.
  - Pepsinogen ORD [Optical Rotatory Dispersion], 1965 1967 1968 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - ORD S [Succinyl] - Pepsinogen, 1966-1968
    - pp. 1-110 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - pp. 111-156 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Tryptic Digest of S-Pepsinogen results, 1967-1968 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    Includes table of contents of designated experiments.
  - Pepsinogen-Structural
    - Amino acid analyses, 1967-1968 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Chromatographs pp. 1-79, 1967-1968 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Chromatographs pp. 80-164, 1967-1968 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - ORD CN-Pepsinogen, 1966-1968 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - ORD Summaries, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
    Includes Pg, CN-Pg, 31CN-Pg, S-Pg.
  - Donna Albertson [technician] notes on Pepsin-pepsinogen (miscellaneous experimental data), 1968 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Pepsinogen - CN Br, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - pH2 and pH4 Pepsins, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Amino acid analyses pH2 and pH4 pepsins and pepsinogens, 1968 September-1969 January (Box 47, Folder 4)
    Includes index to AAA [amino acid analyses] number.
  - Pg and modified Pg CD[Circular Dichroism], 1968 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - ORD-CD Pepsin-pH, 1968-1970 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - ORD-CD Pepsin + Substrate, 1969-1970
    - pp. 1-79 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - pp. 80-153 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - ORD-CD Red-Ox [Reduced oxidized] Pepsin and Pepsinogen, 1969
    - pp. 1-66 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - pp. 67-143 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Nov. Rosie C. Wong notes - Carbamylation of porcine pepsin, 1969; 1 bound notebook (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Reduction of pepsinogen, 1969
    - pp. 0-100 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - pp. 101-213 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Reduction and oxidation of Pgn [Pepsinogen] Chromatograms, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Reduction of pepsin, 1969-1970
    - pp. 1-103 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - pp. 104-190 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Peptide around S-S linkage, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Pepsins CD studies, 1970
    Includes table of contents; typescript draft of Summary of CD and Activities Studies.
    - pp. 1-59 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - pp. 60-126 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - CD and ORD citraconyl pepsinogen, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Beate Ostreicher notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Includes typescript draft "The tryptic digestion of pepsinogen. Separation and amino acid composition of the tryptic peptides" and typewritten notes.
  - Gossypol-pgn I, 1970 (Box 50)
    Includes table of contents to chromatograms.
    - pp. 1-100 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - pp. 101-202 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Gossypol-pgn II, 1970-1971 (Box 51)
    Includes table of contents to chromatograms on pp. 191 and 192.
    - pp. 1-87 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - pp. 88-175 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - pp. 176-260 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Modified pgn tryptic digest AAA [amino acid analyses], 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Pgn - Modification of lysine, 1971
    - pp. 1-115 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - pp. 116-218 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Phosvitin Notes (Box 51)
    - Phosvitin - Amino acid analyses, 1962 1963
      Sam Allerton notes
      - pp. 1-29 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - pp. 30-62 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Phosvitin, 1963-1964; Primarily photocopied notes (Box 52, Folder 1)
      Includes typescript of 1964 Mar. S.E. Allerton grant report on phosvitin. Copies from S. Allerton notes.
    - Phosvitin pH-Urea ORD, 1966 1968 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Phosvitin - Preparations and Analyses, 1965, 1967-1971
      Includes table of contents to hand numbered pages of Procedures, Summary of results; 1 item correspondence 1965 Dec. Allerton/Perlmann with 3 page photocopied notes; Mano and Lipmann published paper.
      - pp. 1-90 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - pp. 91-184 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Computer sheets - Pepsinogen and Phosvitin Group of computer sheets programmed by D. Cantor testing samples of pg and phosvitin, 1968? (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Phosvitin Temperature ORD, 1967-1969 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Phosvitin (Sara Rimon notes)
      - Phosvitin I, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Phosvitin III, 1968-1969 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Phosvitin Ionic Strength ORD, 1968-1969
      - pp. 1-71 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - pp. 72-124 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Phosvitin Ionic Strength CD, 1968-1969 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Dephosphorylation of phosvitin/other results R.S. [Ruth Shainkin notes], 1968-1969 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Phosvitin CD Glycol-pH, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Phosvitin ORD Glycol-pH, 1969-1970 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Phosvitin AAA [amino acid analyses] R.S. [Ruth Shainkin notes], 1969-1970 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Phosvitin - Carbohydrates: R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes
      - Phosvitin - Carbohydrates I, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Phosvitin - Carbohydrates II, 1969-1970 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Phosvitin glycopeptides R.S. [Ruth Shainkin notes), 1969-1971
      - pp. 0-130 (Box 55, Folder 1)
        Includes typescript "Pronase digest of phosvitin".
      - pp. 131-227 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - pp. 228-329 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Peptides of phosvitin D, F, G.R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Phosvitin peptides: R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes, 1970
      - pp. 1-89 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - pp. 90-166 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Phosvitin ORD Low Temperature, 1969-1971
      - pp. 1-43 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - pp. 44-75 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Phosvitin Org. solvents ORD-CD, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Phosvitin org. solvents summary, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Phosvitin methanol ORD-CD, 1970 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Phosvitin ORD-CD, 1970 1972 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - ORD Phosvitin complexes I, 1970-1971
      - pp. 1-88 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - pp. 89-167 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - ORD Phosvitin complexes II, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - CD Phosvitin complexes, 1970-1971 (Box 57)
      - pp. 1-87 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - pp. 88-135 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Felicia Gaskin notes, 1971-1972 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - 1 bound notebook of assorted experiments
    - Dephosphorylation of phosvitin F.G. [Felicia Gaskin] notes, 1971-1972 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Hydrogen exchange of pepsinogen and pepsin. F.G. [Felicia Gaskin] photocopied notes, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      Includes phosvitin notes.
    - Marie Chiao notes, 1971
      Includes egg yolk, non-fert. egg experiments; amino acid analyses and others.
      - pp. 1-94 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - pp. 95-190 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Marie Chiao notes, 1972-1973
      Includes fert., non-fert. egg yolk experiments and others.
      - pp. 1-85 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - pp. 86-168 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - AAA [Amino acid analyses] fert. + non-fert. eggs, 1971-1972 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Summary fert. egg experiments. E.P. [?] notes, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Phosvitin binding experiments
    - Phosvitin binding chromatography, 1971-1972
      - pp. 1-115 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - pp. 116-235 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Phosvitin binding dialysis, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Phosvitin binding various, 1972-1973
      - pp. 1-50 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - pp. 51-114 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Phosvitin binding ORD-CD MeOH I, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Ion binding in MeOH by phosvitin II, undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Binding by phosvitin summaries, 1973
      - pp. 0-94 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - pp. 95-206 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - MgH-CaH phosvitin ORD-CD, 1972-1973 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Phosvitin embryogenesis R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] and E.P. [?] notes Amino acid analyses, 1972-1973 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      Includes typescript draft of amino acid analyzer operating instructions.
    - Phosvitin miscellaneous Data and notes on chromatography; amino acid analyses; alkaline hydrolysis of PV [phosvitin], 1971 1974 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Phosvitin summary, undated (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Phosvitin Preps/Analyses
      - 1970-1972 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Phosvitin work in progress, 1973 1974 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Brain phosphoproteins R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] note, 1968-1969 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      Includes notes other than pepsin-pepsinogen phosvitin
    - A.A.A. [amino acid analyses] Edman degradation - R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes, 1969-1970 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Carbohydrates - R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes, 1969-1970 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Destruct. of Psr., Ptr - R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes - amino acid analyses, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - p-threonine; p-serine C4II-R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes, 1971
      Includes some phosvitin analyses.
      - pp. 1-88 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - pp. 89-150 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - p-threonine C4II Edman degradation R.S. [Ruth Shainkin] notes, 1971
      - pp. 1-49 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - pp. 50-123 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Protamine-polylysines, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      Includes 2 items Sigma/Perlmann correspondence.
- Collection of laboratory notes and manuscripts
  Miscellaneous laboratory equipment information.
  Arranged either by individual worker or subject (Perlmann subject arrangement maintained). In alphabetical order.
  - Allerton, Samuel. Report material on "Studies on phosvitin", 1963 September 27 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    Includes typescript of report with notes.
  - Enzyme Preparations (Box 63, Folder 2)
    Procedures by Kornberg and Volkin.
  - Katchalski, A. Laboratory notes, 1962 1963 1964 1965 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Katchalski, E., Blout, E. - Boston (NIH Gulticl data) (Box 63, Folder 4)
    Typescript 1st draft with corrections of ms "Polyamino acids as protein models" by E. Katchalski with notes.
  - Katchalski, E., Kauzman, W. Pepsinogen notes, 1962 1963 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Koehn, Paul V. Laboratory notes (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Koshland, Dr. (Box 63, Folder 7)
    Chymotrypsin, Opt. Rot. measurements, graphs.
  - Laboratory Equipment Miscellaneous (Box 63, Folder 8)
    Includes: Procedure for Automatic Amino Acid Analyzer of Spinco Model Polarimeter. Reader attachment specifications; equipment costs; expenses.
  - NEM [N-ethylmaleimide] derivatives 1961 Typescript (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Ong, Eng Bee, 1966 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    Figures; outline summary; typescript first draft of ms "A comparative study of the specificity of water-soluble trypsin with that of water-insoluble copoly - (maleic acid-ethylene) - trypsin".
  - Optical Rotation Gastricin miscellaneous laboratory notes (Box 63, Folder 11)
    Measurements; graphs; laboratory notes.
  - Pepsinogen-Fluorescence; Pepsin; Worthington, 1963 1966 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    Includes:.
    Fluorescence: 1963 notes and graphs; Gally and Edelman reprint of published paper.
    Pepsin: Typescripts of Rajagopalan, Stein and Moore 1966 mss.
    Worthington: 1 item correspondence concerning samples of pepsinogen.
  - Plakalbumin Reports [G.E. Perlmann] (Box 63, Folder 13)
    Danish material:.
    Includes various reports [internal evidence indicates reports are from G.E. Perlmann to Linderstrøm-Lang] reprints of published papers, one by Perlmann.
  - Trypsin-Immunology (Box 63, Folder 14)
    Typescript draft of experiment results with graphs.
  - Yphantis, David (For transition curves) (Box 63, Folder 15)
    Laboratory notes includes measurements; calculations; graphs.
- Photographic negatives, 1948-1974; 143 envelopes of 5 × 7 photographic negatives
  Tables, charts, graphs, illustrations of laboratory work and results used in publications and lectures. Envelopes contain more than 1 negative.
  - 1948, 6 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1949, 5 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
    Includes glass negative.
  - 1950, 3 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1951, 5 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1952, 7 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1953, 3 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1954, 5 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
    Includes 3 x 4 glass negative.
  - 1955, 2 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1956, 1 envelope with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1957, 6 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1958, 9 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1959, 12 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1960, 3 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1961, 7 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1962, 11 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1963, 6 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1964, 5 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1965, 4 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1966, 7 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1967, 7 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1968, 7 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1969, 4 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1970, 4 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
    Includes 2 photographic prints.
  - 1971, 5 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1973, 7 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
  - 1974, 2 envelopes with negatives (Box 64)
    Includes photographic print.
- Photographic prints (Box 65)
  Tables, graphs, charts illustrations of laboratory readings and results. Used in publications and lectures.
  Includes some 5 x 7 negatives, 2 x 2 lantern slides. Dating supplied from negatives (Box no. 64).
  - Lantern slide material. Miscellaneous material includes duplicates, 1950-1954 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Lantern slides - Boston (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Lantern slides - Experimental Burns (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Lantern slides - Casein, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Lantern slides - Dephosphorylation of proteins, 1950-1952 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Lantern slides - Plakalbumin and Immun, 1949 1951 1954 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Crystals, 1962; 2 + 1 items (Box 65, Folder 7)
    Includes duplicates; (2) 2 x 2 lantern slides 1 of which is a duplicate; (1) 3 x 4 colored glass slide.
  - Phosvitin work used in publication as identified, 1970-1975 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    Includes duplicates; 5 x 7 negatives and 2 x 2 lantern slides for #91 in bibliography.
    Mss. # in bibliography Figures.
    74 1-6.
    75 1, 4-9.
    77 1-6.
    81 5.
    87 1-12.
    89 1, 3, 4.
    90 2-4.
    91 1-3, 5, 6.
    Includes 5 x 7 negatives and 2 x 2 lantern slides.
    Arranged in numerical order as to bibliography mss #.
  - Phosvitin. Unidentified as to publication (Box 65, Folder 9)
    Includes duplicates.
- Glass slides, 122 items
  Charts, graphs, tables of laboratory readings and results.
  Includes: 3 x 4 glass slides, some black framed, most aluminum framed.
  Arranged in chronological order: [removed from wooden slide drawers].
  - 1956, 1 item (Box 66)
  - 1960, 1 item (Box 66)
  - 1961, 8 items (Box 66)
  - 1962, 21 items (Box 66)
  - 1963, 15 items (Box 66)
  - 1964, 12 items (Box 66)
  - 1965, 12 items (Box 66)
  - 1966, 35 items (Box 66)
  - 1967, 13 items (Box 66)
  - 1968, 1 item colored (Box 66)
  - undated, 3 items (Box 66)
    Includes 1 colored.
  - 3 x 4 glass slides boxed, 13 items (Box 66)
    - 1962, 2 items
    - 1965, 2 items
    - 1968, 9 items
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides boxed, 9 items (Box 66)
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides labelled Tom - Felicia - boxed, 15 items (Box 66)
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides boxed (slides numbered 1-24), 24 items (Box 66)
  - 3 x 4 black framed slides. Some marked Massachusetts General Hospital, some are dated [Internal evidence indicates some used for 1957 Nov. 20 Mount Holyoke Lecture on Proteins], Kept in order found, 1957 November 20; 49 items (Box 67)
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides in box marked "Leitz". In slide # numerical order, 34 items (Box 67)
  - 3 x 4 aluminum framed glass slides boxed. Kept in order found, 17 items (Box 67)
    - colored, undated; 5 items
    - 1965, 11 items
    - undated, 1 item
    - 3 x 4 aluminum framed glass slides boxed, 1967; 13 items
  - Glass slides: Plates of experimental work 2 x 10 glass plates include (Box 68)